Guide to the Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Business Papers, 1679-1802; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Legal Documents
    - Other Legal Documents
      - Acknowledgment of receipt of money from Ralph Payne to Charles Pearce, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 293)
      - Assignment of money from Drewry Ottley to Ralph Payne in trust, 1772 (Box 10, Folder 294)
    - Payne & Leigh Shipping Papers
      - Accounts, shares, and related papers, 1749-1772
- Accounts, Bills and Receipts, 1726-1807; Series VI; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series VI, Accounts, Bills and Receipts, is divided into four subseries: Ralph Payne (d. 1763); Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington (1739-1807); Stephen Payne (d. 1772); and Other Accounts.The first three are chronologically arranged; the items have been roughly sorted by year. This series contains a wealth of information on all types of financial transactions, from bills of exchange through a 1752 receipt for "30 fine brilliant diamonds" and for "building the steps to the organ Loft" for a church in St. Kitts. The "accounts of sundries" frequently contain information on the purchase of individual slaves, listed alongside farming and sugarmaking supplies and "sundries from London." In addition to the above types of information, the accounts of Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington also include information on his expenditures during his governorships. The folders of receipts and bills covering his sojourn in England, although obviously very incomplete, document his aristocratic tastes in clothing, food and household goods as well as his increasing indebtedness and frequent inability to raise small sums of cash. Stephen Payne's accounts are more tightly focused on his work as a manager and overseer for his more prosperous relatives. "Other Accounts" contains single items and small groups of financial records related to individuals, almost all of whom did business with Stephen Payne. They have been left in the order in which they were received, filed by personal name.
  - Ralph Payne (d. 1763)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1742-1749 (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1750-1759 (Box 11, Folder 296-302)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1760-1766, undated (Box 11, Folder 303-307)
  - Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington (1739-1807)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1765-1770 (Box 12, Folder 308-310)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1771-1779 (Box 12, Folder 311-315)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1780-1789 (Box 12, Folder 316-323)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1790-1799 (Box 13, Folder 324-330)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, 1800-1807 (Box 13, Folder 331-340)
    - Accounts, bills and receipts, undated (Box 13, Folder 341-344)
  - Stephen Payne (d. 1772)
    - Bills and receipts, 1744-1749 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    - Bills and receipts, 1750-1755 (Box 14, Folder 346)
    - Bills and receipts, 1756-1759 (Box 14, Folder 347-349)
    - Bills and receipts, 1760-1764 (Box 14, Folder 350-354)
    - Bills and receipts, 1765-1769 (Box 14, Folder 355-359)
    - Bills and receipts, 1770-1772 (Box 14, Folder 360-361)
    - Bills and receipts, undated (Box 14, Folder 362)
  - Other Accounts
    - Adye, Stephen and Clara, 1757-1764, undated (Box 15, Folder 363-364)
    - Alford, Daniel, 1735-1769 (Box 15, Folder 365-366)
      See also: Oversize, Box 17, folder 443
    - Audain, ?, undated (Box 15, Folder 367)
    - Baker, Jonathan, 1767 (Box 15, Folder 368)
    - Barry, Jonas, 1753-1754 (Box 15, Folder 369)
    - Buckley, William, 1756 (Box 15, Folder 370)
    - Colman, Francis, 1732 (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - Constantine, Henry, 1755 (Box 15, Folder 372)
    - Crooke, Charles, 1769 (Box 15, Folder 373)
    - Dewitt, Phillip, 1731 (Box 15, Folder 374)
    - Douglas, John, 1753 (Box 15, Folder 375)
    - Dunbavin, Nicolas, 1748-1751 (Box 15, Folder 376)
    - Edmeads, Thomas, 1761 (Box 15, Folder 377)
    - Estridge, William, 1728-1732, undated (Box 15, Folder 378)
    - Fahie, John, 1761 (Box 15, Folder 379)
    - Gaines, Frances, 1748 (Box 15, Folder 380)
    - Gallwey, Anne, 1759 (Box 15, Folder 381)
    - Gallwey, Mathew Mills, 1759 (Box 15, Folder 382)
    - Georges, William Payne, 1760 (Box 15, Folder 383)
    - Gibbon, Robert, 1764-1770 (Box 15, Folder 384)
    - Gray, John, 1752-1761 (Box 15, Folder 385)
    - Holmes, Richard, 1754 (Box 15, Folder 386)
    - Johnson, Nathaniel, 1758 (Box 15, Folder 387)
    - Markham, Benjamin, 1726-1738 (Box 15, Folder 388)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 438
    - McKenly, James, 1754 (Box 15, Folder 389)
    - Morgan, Robert, 1750 (Box 15, Folder 390)
    - Orton, Jane, 1755-1765 (Box 15, Folder 391)
    - Ottley, Thomas, 1734-1786 (Box 15, Folder 392)
    - Parsons, Edward, 1754-1759 (Box 15, Folder 393)
    - Payne, Ann, 1766-1779 (Box 15, Folder 394-395)
    - Payne, Charles, 1747-1760 (Box 15, Folder 396)
    - Payne, Edward, 1760-1764 (Box 15, Folder 397)
    - Payne, Gilles, 1746-1764 (Box 15, Folder 398)
    - Payne, Joseph, 1750 (Box 15, Folder 399)
    - Payne, Richard, 1741-1751 (Box 15, Folder 400-401)
    - Payne, Willett, 1756-1757 (Box 15, Folder 402)
    - Payne, ?, 1756-1770, undated (Box 15, Folder 403)
    - Percival, James, 1752 (Box 15, Folder 404)
    - Priddie, William, 1761-1769 (Box 15, Folder 405)
    - Purcell, James, 1750-1754 (Box 15, Folder 406)
    - Symonds, James, 1758-1759 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Taylor, Sam Okes, 1760 (Box 15, Folder 408)
    - Thibou, Daniel, 1758 (Box 15, Folder 409)
    - Warner, Thomas, 1772 (Box 15, Folder 410)
    - Willett, Martha, 1756-1758 (Box 15, Folder 411)
    - Willett, Ralph, 1756-1761 (Box 15, Folder 412-414)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 439
- Oversize, 3.01; (2 boxes)
  - Warner, Thomas (Series I), 1754 Oct 19 (Box 16, Folder 415)
  - Questions and draft answers concerning Commodore Moore's conduct (Series II), [1760] (Box 16, Folder 416)
  - "Additional Instructions" (Series II), 1772 Jul 1 (Box 16, Folder 417)
  - "Answer upon the Presentation of the Sword from the Legislature of Antigua" (Series II), [1775?] (Box 16, Folder 418)
  - Richard Downing's patent from King George I (Series II), 1724 Jun 1 (Box 16, Folder 419)
  - Petition of the Lieutenant Governor and Assembly of the Virgin Islands concerning Tortola (Series II), 1774 May 7 (Box 16, Folder 420)
  - "Copy of a Letter from Mr. Fahie" (Series II), 1774 May 8 (Box 16, Folder 421)
  - Petition of John Downing Junior and others concerning Tortola (Series II), 1774 Aug 2 (Box 16, Folder 422)
  - "Memorial of John Downing Junior Esq." (Series II), 1776 Nov 20 (Box 16, Folder 423)
  - "A List of Negroes Cattle Horses Mules Buildings Utensils &c on the estate in Antigua called Carliles..." (Series III), 1774 Jan 1 (Box 16, Folder 424)
  - "Sales of Negroes belonging to the Right Honourable Lord Lavington..." (Series III), 1796-1797 (Box 16, Folder 425)
  - Assignment of mortgage of Brodbelt plantation from Sir Ralph Payne to Ralph Willett: draft (2 copies) (Series III), 1775 (Box 16, Folder 426-427)
  - Indenture from Mary Elliott to Ralph Payne (Series III), 1747 Dec 31 (Box 16, Folder 428)
  - Plantation in Sulphur's Gutt: Indenture between Richard and Elizabeth Kirwan and Ralph Payne (Series III), 1749 Feb 21 (Box 16, Folder 429)
  - Release from Edward Byam to Sir Ralph Payne (2 copies) (Series III), 1773 Nov 26 (Box 16, Folder 430-431)
  - Articles of Agreement for a Co-Partnership (Series III), 1752 May 4 (Box 16, Folder 432)
  - Bond for performance of lease between Valentine French and Martin Blake (Series III), 1738 Apr 13 (Box 16, Folder 433)
  - Indenture between Philip Audain and Zachariah Bourryau (Series III), 1740 Jun 11 (Box 16, Folder 434)
  - Attested copy of a grant from King George III to William Fitzhugh of a plantation in the parish of St. David (Series III), 1768 Jul 8 (Box 16, Folder 435)
  - Accounts with Truman, Neave & Willett (Series IV), 1764-68 (Box 16, Folder 436)
  - Payne & Leigh shipping papers: accounts, shares, and related papers (Series V), 1749-1772 (Box 16, Folder 437)
  - Markham, Benjamin (Series VI), 1726-1738 (Box 16, Folder 438)
  - Articles of Agreement between the King and Christopher Stoddard (Series III), 1726 Sep 23 (Box 17, Folder 439)
  - Articles of Agreement between the King and the Rev. Walter Thomas (Series III), 1732 May 9 (Box 17, Folder 440)
  - Articles of Agreement between the King and the Rev. Walter Thomas (Series III), 1737 Aug 10 (Box 17, Folder 441)
  - Release from John Pogson to Ralph Payne, executor of Stephen Adye's estate (Series V), 1760 Apr 4 (Box 17, Folder 442)
  - Alford, Daniel: Accounts (Series VI), 1735-1769 (Box 17, Folder 443)
- Oversize Parchment (from Series III), 1; (1 box)
  The material in Box 18 may be seen only with the permission of the appropriate curator. In some cases, conservation work to an item may be necessary before the item can be consulted.
  - Conveyance from Lord Lavington and others to William Farmerie in trust, 1801 Jun 25 (Box 18, Folder 444)
  - Grant from King George II to Ralph Payne, 1757 Mar 7 (Box 18, Folder 445)
  - Tripartite indenture of release from Maitland & Boddington to John Mills et. al., 1766 Dec 5 (Box 18, Folder 446)
  - Mortgage in fee from Sir Ralph Payne to Charles Pearce, 1771 Nov 18 (Box 18, Folder 447)
  - Indenture and conveyance in four parts: Maynard and Fraser, 1789 Nov 17 (Box 18, Folder 448)
  - Tripartite indenture from Edward Jessup and members of the Dewitt family to Ralph Payne, 1745 May 27 (Box 18, Folder 449)
  - Indenture between Richard and Elizabeth Kirwan and Ralph Payne, 1749 Feb 21 (Box 18, Folder 450)
  - Indenture from John Richardson to Papillon Ball, 1739 Aug 2 (Box 18, Folder 451)
  - Counterpart of grant of an annuity by Ralph Payne and Samuel Martin to Thomas Walter of Nevis, 1752 Dec 16 (Box 18, Folder 452)
  - Deed of indenture from John Symonds to Ralph Payne, 1762 May 31 (Box 18, Folder 453)
  - Indenture and release from Ralph Payne to Henry Wilmot, 1764 Jun 4 (Box 18, Folder 454)
  - Indenture and release from Ralph Payne to Valentine Allott, 1768 Mar 3, 4 (Box 18, Folder 455)
  - Indenture and release from Drewry Ottley to Ralph Payne, 1769 Jun 16 (Box 18, Folder 456)
  - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Thomas Tyson, 1731 (Box 18, Folder 457)
  - Indenture confirming articles of agreement between John Douglas, Peter Mitchell, and others regarding a joint boiling house, [1730 Feb?] (Box 18, Folder 458)
- Oversize Broadside, 1786 Dec 1
  - Deed of trust from Sir Ralph Payne to Godschall Johnson (Series III), 1786 Dec 1 (Box bsd, Folder 459)
  - Surrender of trust from Godschall Johnson to Sir Ralph Payne and Deed of Trust from Sir Ralph Payne to Messrs. Nesbitt and Stewart (Series III), 1789 Dec 31 (Box bsd, Folder 460)
  - Articles of agreement between John and Elizabeth Carlisle Gray and Ralph Payne for obtaining an Act of Assembly concerning the plantations in Antigua (Series III), 1752 Dec 26 (Box bsd, Folder 461)
  - Royal Proclamation of the Act of Assembly concerning the plantations in Antigua (Series III), 1754 Jul 21 (Box bsd, Folder 462)
  - Indenture and conveyance from Bartholomew Rees to Rowland Tryon and William Tryon of sugar works and plantations on Montserrat, including "Calk Hill" (Series III), 1705 May 8 (Box bsd, Folder 463)
  - Indenture and conveyance from William Tryon to Robert Cunningham of two sugar works and plantations on Montserrat, Cork Hill and a plantation in St. Anthony's Parish (Series III), 1732 Feb 9 (Box bsd, Folder 464)
  - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Ralph Payne (Series III), 1737 Sep 20 (Box bsd, Folder 465)
  - Indenture between John Ward and Thomas Mills (Series III), 1760 Dec 2 (Box bsd, Folder 466)
  - Indenture between John Helden and Gilbert Fleming (Series III), 1729 Dec 24 (Box bsd, Folder 467)
  - Indenture between Dominick Henry Trant of Montserrat and Archibald Esdail (Series III), 1768 Oct 12 (Box bsd, Folder 468)
  - Mortgage from Valentine French to Martin Blake (Series III), 1736 Jul 16 (Box bsd, Folder 469)
  - Indenture between William Mathew, Gilbert Fleming, and John Willet and the Rev. Walter Thomas (Series III), 1742 Jun 16 (Box bsd, Folder 470)
  - Indenture between John and Mary Neal, Elizabeth Clay, Sarah Robinson, and Ann Williams and the Rev. Walter Thomas (Series III), 1746 Sep 5 (Box bsd, Folder 471)
  - Indenture between the Rev. Walter Thomas and Ralph Payne (Series III), 1747 Mar 26 (Box bsd, Folder 472)
  - Duplicate mortgage by Cauldwell Craig Esq. to James Ballmer Esq. (Series III), 1773 Jan 6 (Box bsd, Folder 473)
  - "Purchase of interests in Plantation, Buildings, 82 Slaves, Cattle, etc. in the West Indies" (incomplete) (Series III), 1775 (Box bsd, Folder 474)
  - Agreement between the King and Christopher Stoddard (Series IV), 1726 Sep 23 (Box bsd, Folder 475)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Box 19 contains fragile originals. The material may be seen only with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 6 (Box 19, Folder 476)
  - Box 1, folder 36 (Box 19, Folder 477)
  - Box 1, folder 47 (Box 19, Folder 478)
  - Box 2, folder 74 (Box 19, Folder 479)
  - Box 2, folder 84 (Box 19, Folder 480)
  - Box 2, folder 93 (Box 19, Folder 481)
  - Box 3, folder 105 (Box 19, Folder 482)
  - Box 3, folder 106 (Box 19, Folder 483)
  - Box 5, folder 151 (Box 19, Folder 484)
  - Box 6, folder 183 (Box 19, Folder 485)
  - Box 6, folder 184 (Box 19, Folder 486)
  - Box 7, folder 206 (Box 19, Folder 487)
  - Box 9, folder 238 (Box 19, Folder 488)
  - Box 10, folder 269 (Box 19, Folder 489)
  - Box 10, folder 288 (Box 19, Folder 490)
  - Box 10, folder 290 (Box 19, Folder 491)
  - Box 11, folder 307 (Box 19, Folder 492)
  - Box 15, folder 363 (Box 19, Folder 493)
  - Box 17, folder 440 (Box 19, Folder 494)